A Guide the Max Theiler family papers FA486
Rockefeller Archive Center
Max Theiler family papers
1891-1990
Rockefeller Archive Center
Theiler, Max
Rockefeller Foundation
Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health
FA486
4.42 Cubic Feet
13 boxes.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Series 1: Arnold Theiler. Subseries 1.1: Obituaries and Memorials. Subseries 1.2: Reprints.
Series 2: Max Theiler.
Series 3: Photographs. Subseries 3.1: Arnold Theiler photographs. Subseries 3.2: Max Theiler photographs.
Series 4: Ephemera.
Biographical / Historical
Arnold Theiler (1867 March 26-1936 July 24) is commonly considered to be the father of veterinary science in South Africa.
Max Theiler (1899 January 30– 1972 August 11), Arnold's son, was a virologist and doctor awarded the 1951 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine for his 1937 efforts to develop a yellow fever vaccine.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: correspondence, obituaries, reprints, and photographs.
- Arnold Theiler, 1
  - "Arnold Theiler 1867-1936, His Life and Times," compiled by Gertrud Theiler, 1966 August-October (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Typescript with corrections and annotations; includes "Reminiscences" by J. H. R. Bischop
  - "Arnold Theiler 1867-1936, His Life and Times," by Gertrud Theiler, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Typescript; includes copy of Letter from Gertrud Theiler to Max and Lillian Theiler, 1972 July 5
  - "Arnold Theiler 1867-1936: His Life and Times" by Gertrud Theiler, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Publikasies van die Universiteit van Pretoria, Nuwe Reeks NR. 61
  - "As I Remember Him," by Gertrud Theiler, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Reminiscences" (of Arnold Theiler), by J.H.R. Bischop, circa 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "There was a Man: The Life and Times of Sir Arnold Theiler, K.C.M.G. of Onderstepoort," by Thelma Gutsche (Box 1, Folder 6)
    publication notice.
  - "Letters from Arnold Theiler to His Parents, Franz and Marie Theiler" (Handwritten, First English Draft.), 1891-1901 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Handwritten, First English Draft. Compiled by Alfred Theiler; translated from the German by Max Theiler.
  - "Letters from Arnold Theiler to His Parents, Franz and Marie Theiler" (First Typed Draft.), 1891-1901 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    First Typed Draft. Compiled by Alfred Theiler; translated from the German by Max Theiler.
  - "Letters from Arnold Theiler to His Parents, Franz and Marie Theiler" (Corrected Typed Draft.), 1891-1901 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Corrected Typed Draft. Compiled by Alfred Theiler; translated from the German by Max Theiler.
  - "Letters from Arnold Theiler to His Parents, Franz and Marie Theiler" (Final Draft.), 1891-1901; Copy 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Final Draft. Compiled by Alfred Theiler; translated from the German by Max Theiler.
  - "Letters from Arnold Theiler to His Parents, Franz and Marie Theiler" (Final Draft.), 1891-1901; Copy 2 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Arnold Theiler, by Alfred Theiler, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Notes and map used in "Letters from Arnold Theiler to His Parents"
  - Letters from Arnold Theiler to Emma Theiler, 1899-1900 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes note by G. (Gertrud Theiler?), July 28, 1972: "A batch of war letters from Father to Mother. Typed separately for easy insertion into the more fulsome collection which was sent to Grandfather.")
  - Biography of Franz Theiler, by Alfred Theiler, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Equine Research Hall of Fame Induction, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Equine Research Hall of Fame Induction, 1990 December 1; Plaque (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Obituaries and Memorials, 1.1
    - Obituaries and Memorials, 1936-1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Obituary by Max Kupfer, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Obituary by G. Senn, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Arnold Theiler Memorial Issue, Journal of the South African Veterinary Medical Association, 1936 December (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "The Life and Work of Sir Arnold Theiler," P. J. du Toit and Cecil Jackson, 1936 December; Photocopy. (Box 3, Folder 22)
      From Journal of the South African Veterinary Medical Association, 1936 December
    - Obituary, The Veterinary Record, 1936 August (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Reprints, 1.2
    - Reprint, "Experimentaluntersuchungen uber Rinderpest," Arnold Theiler, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Reprint, "Rinderpest in Sud-Afrika," Arnold Theiler, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Reprint, "Die Tsetse-Krankheit," Arnold Theiler, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Reprint, "Die Malaria des Pferdes," Arnold Theiler, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Reprint, "Some Diseases of the Horse in South Africa," Arnold Theiler, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Reprint, "Rhodesian Tick Fever," Arnold Theiler, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Reprint, "Die Piroplasmosis des Maulthieres und des Esels," Arnold Theiler, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Reprint, "Beitrag zur Frage der Immunitat der Piroplasmosis des Hundes, Vorlaufige Mitteilung," Arnold Theiler, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Reprint, "Transvaalsche Veterinargesellschaft zu Pratoria", 1904 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Reprint, "Maladies des Troupeaux dans L'Afrique du Sud," Arnold Theiler, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Reprint, "Transmission and Innoculability of Spirillum Theiler (Laveran)," Arnold Theiler, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Reprint, "Das Katarrhalfieber der Schafe in Sudafrika," Arnold Theiler, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Reprint, "Anaplasma Marginale, A New Genus and Species of the Protozoa," Arnold Theiler, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Reprint, "Anaplasma Marginale (Genus nov. et species nov.): Un Nouveau Protozoaire du Betail," Arnold Theiler, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Reprint, "De Voorkoming en Uitroeiing van Oostkustkoorts," Arnold Theiler and J. M. Christy, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Reprint, "Transmission of Amakebe by Means of Rhipicephalus Appendiculatus, the Brown Tick," Arnold Theiler, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Reprint, "Interim Report re the Dosing of Sheep with Cooper's Dip and Bluestone, under the Conditions of a Sourveld Farm," Arnold Theiler, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Reprint, "President's Address," Arnold Theiler, South African Journal of Science, 1912 September (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Reprint, "Das Trypanblau und Trypanrot in der Behandlung der Piroplasmosen und deren praktische und theoretische Bedeutung," Arnold Theiler, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Reprint, "Zeitschrift fur Infektionskrankheiten, parasitare Krankheiten und Hygiene der Haustiere," Arnold Theiler and Wolff Hugel, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Reprint, "Das Arsenikbad und seine Verwendung zur Bexampfung der Zecken und der von diesen ubertragenen Tierkrankheiten," Arnold Theiler, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Reprint, "Immunization against Animal Diseases," Arnold Theiler, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Reprint, "De Resultaten van de Laatste Onderzoekingen Omtrent Lamziekte," Arnold Theiler, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Reprint, "Investigations into the Life-History of the Wire-Worm in Ostriches," Arnold Theiler and W. Robertson, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Reprint, "A New Nematode in Fowls, Having a Termite as an Intermediary Host," Arnold Theiler, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Reprint, "Contagious Abortion in Cattle," Arnold Theiler, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Reprint, "Slapziekte in Horses in Griqualand West (Dourine)," Arnold Theiler, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Reprint, "Veeartsenijonderwijs en-Ondersoek in Suidafrika," Arnold Theiler, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Reprint, "Diseases, Ticks, and Their Eradication," Arnold Theiler, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Reprint, "Phosphorus in the Live Stock Industry," Arnold Theiler, H. H. Green, and P. J. du Toit, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Reprint, "The Transmission of Tick-Borne Diseases by the Intrajugular Injection of the Emulsified Intermediary Host Itself," Arnold Theiler and P. J. du Toit, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Reprint, "Equine Parabotulism," Arnold Theiler and E. M. Robinson, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Reprint, "La Transmission des Maladies dont les Tiques sont les Vecteurs par l'injection intrajugulaire d'une emulsion de l'hote intermediaire," Arnold Theiler, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Reprint, "Minimum Mineral Requirements in Cattle," Arnold Theiler, H. H. Green, and P. J. du Toit, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Reprint, "Der Botulismus der Haustiere: Definition, Historisches, Literatur-Ubersicht, Experimentelles," Arnold Theiler and E. M. Robinson, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Reprint, "Die Diplodiosis der Rinder und Schafe in Sud-Afrika," Arnold Theiler, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Reprint, "Ecthyma Contagiosum of Sheep and Goats," Arnold Theiler, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Reprint, "Gonderia Mutans or Theileria Mutans?," Arnold Theiler and H. Graf, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Reprint, "Botulism (Parabotulism) in Equines," Arnold Theiler and E. M. Robinson, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Reprint, "Theileroise Sud-Africaine Experimentale Transmise par le Sang," Arnold Theiler and P. J. du Toit, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Reprint, "Address on Research Work in Pastoral Problems," Arnold Theiler, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Reprint, "Quelques Observations Recentes sur la Nature de Gonderia Mutans," Arnold Theiler and H. Graf, 1928; 2 copies. (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Reprint, "The Transmission of East Coast Fever by Means of Blood," Arnold Theiler and P. J. du Toit, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Reprint, "The Health and Nutrition of Animals," Arnold Theiler and J. B. Orr, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Reprint, "African Horse Sickness," Arnold Theiler, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Reprint, "Un Nouveau Medicament pour le Traitement des Piroplasmoses," Arnold Theiler, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Reprint, "The Pathological Aspect of Phosphorus and Calcium Deficiency in Cattle," Arnold Theiler, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Reprint, "L'Aphosphorose Naturelle et Experimentale des Bovides," Arnold Theiler, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Reprint, "Das Phosphordefizit und die Unfruchtbarkeit des Rindes," Arnold Theiler, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Reprint, "Les Dystrophies Osseuses des Animaux Domestiques," Arnold Theiler and H. H. Green, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Reprint, "The Osteodystrophic Diseases of Domesticated Animals: Part 1, The Structure of the Bone, and Part 2, Rickets and Osteomalacia," Arnold Theiler, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Reprint, "The Osteodystrophic Diseases of Domesticated Animals: Part 3, The Osteodystrophia Fibrosa," Arnold Theiler, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Reprint, "Das Widererscheinin der Rinderpest und die Erfolge der Schutzimpfung in Sudafrika," Arnold Theiler, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Reprint, "Die Osteoporosis des Pferdegeschlechtes," Arnold Theiler, undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Reprint, "Weitere Versuche, das Ostkstenfieber durch Zecken zu bertragen," Arnold Theiler, undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Reprint, "Das Knochenfressen der Rinder in Sdafrika," Arnold Theiler, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Reprint, "Ueber eine Ansteckende Mauke," Arnold Theiler, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Reprint, "Rinderpest-Serum und aktive Immunisierung," Arnold Theiler, undated (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Reprint, "Die Theilerschen Forschungs-und Lehrinstitute fr Veterin„rmedizin und Biologie in Sdafrika,"Arnold Theiler, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
- Max Theiler, 2
  - Awards, 1932-1968 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Biographical Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
    Notes by Max Theiler on his schooldays; also includes notes on Arnold Theiler and the establishment of the veterinary research center at Onderstepoort.
  - Biographies: General, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Biographies: "Max Theiler: Yellow Jack and the Jackpot," Elmer Bendiner, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Biographies: "The Sting of Death," Carol Eron, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Biographies: "Max Theiler, Nobel Prize Winner, His Sisters Remember," Margaret and Gertrud Theiler, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Clippings (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Condolences (on death of Max Theiler), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence: General, 1940-1967 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    Includes travelogues by Edward Robinson, 1951-1953; laboratory data on mouse neutralization tests, 1960.
  - Correspondence: Alfred Theiler and Family, 1949-1967 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Correspondence: Max Theiler to Lillian Theiler, 1951; 1955; undated (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 94A)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted from scholarly access.
  - Harvard African Expedition, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Hasle (Switzerland) Celebration (in honor of Max Theiler), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Lasker Award, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Nobel Prize: Announcement and Acceptance, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    Includes Theiler's speech and lecture.
  - Nobel Prize: Ceremonies, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Nobel Prize: Clippings (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Nobel Prize: Clippings (Swedish Newspapers), 1951 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Nobel Prize: Correspondence, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Nobel Prize: Correspondence, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Nobel Prize: Diary of Lillian Theiler, 1951; 2 copies, 1 labeled "incomplete". (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Nobel Prize: American Nobel Anniversary Dinner, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Obituaries, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Presidents (U. S.), 1962-1970 (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Report Cards and Early Records, circa 1905-1926 (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - South African Biological Society Pamphlets, 1948-1951 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Trips: Colombia, 1938 (?) (Box 6, Folder 111)
    Observations on My Trip to Colombia
  - Trips: India, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    Includes trip diary, Egypt and India
  - Trips: Latin America, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    Includes trip diary
  - Trips: Latin America, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Yale Arbovirus Research Unit, Annual Report, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Yale University, 1964-1972 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Reprint, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - "Rat-bite disease in the United States with Report of a Case", 1924 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Reprints, 1924-1931 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "Investigations Concerning Amoebic Dysentery", 1924 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "Special Protozoological Studies of the Blood", circa 1926 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "The Use of Sodoku in the Treatment of General Paralysis", 1926 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "Experimental Rat-Bite Fever", 1926 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "The Immunological Relationship of Yellow Fever as it Occurs in West Africa and in South America", 1928 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "Susceptibility of White Mice to the Virus of Yellow Fever", 1930 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "Studies on the Action of Yellow Fever Virus in Mice", 1930; 2 copies. (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - "Neutralization Tests with Immune Yellow Fever Sera and a Strain of Yellow Fever Virus Adapted to Mice", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Reprints, 1932-1936 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "Studies of Yellow Fever Virus in Tissue Culture", 1932 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "Untersuchungen uber das Verhalten des Gelbfiebervirus in der Gewebekultur", 1932 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "A Yellow Fever Protection Test in Mice by Intracerebral Injection", 1933 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "The Susceptibility of Guinea Pigs to the Virus of Yellow Fever", 1933 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "Spontaneous Encephalomyelitis of Mice: A New Virus Disease", 1934 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "Quantitative Studies of the Virus and Immune Serum Used in Vaccination against Yellow Fever", 1935 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "Studies of Circulating Virus and Protective Antibodies in Susceptible and Relatively Insusceptible Monkeys after Inoculation with Yellow Fever Virus", 1935; 2 copies. (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "Modification of the Virulence of Yellow Fever Virus by Cultivation in Tissues In Vitro", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - "The Use of Hyper-Immune Monkey Serum in Human Vaccination against Yellow Fever", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Reprints, 1937-1968 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "The Effect of Prolonged Cultivation In Vitro upon the Pathogenicity of Yellow Fever Virus", 1937; 2 copies. (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "The Use of Yellow Fever Virus Modified by In Vitro Cultivation for Human Immunization", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "The Adaptation of Unmodified Strains of Yellow Fever Virus to Cultivation In Vitro", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "Encephalomyelitis of Mice, Parts 1-3", 1940 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "Studies of Poliomyelitis", 1941 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "Nobel Lecture: The Development of Vaccines against Yellow Fever", 1951; 2 copies. (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "Relation of Haemaphysalis Spinigera Larval Infection Rates and Host Viremia Levels of Kyasanur Forest Disease Virus," K. R. P. Singh and C. R. Anderson, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 120)
- Photographs, 3
  - Arnold Theiler photographs, 3.1
    - Portrait of Arnold Theiler (Louis Schmidt), 1923 (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Portrait of Arnold Theiler (Louis Schmidt), 1924 (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - Portrait of Arnold Theiler, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - Portrait of Arnold Theiler, 1920s (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Portrait of Arnold Theiler, 1920s (Box 7, Folder 125)
    - Portrait of Arnold Theiler (Steger Studio), undated (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Portrait of Arnold Theiler (Alf. F. Hosking), undated (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Portrait of Arnold Theiler (Lafayette Ltd.), undated; 2 images. (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Group Photo in Laboratory, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 129)
      Unidentified group. Written on back of photo: "Washington, 1934, Arnold Theiler and P. du Toit." Max Theiler in back row, center?
  - Max Theiler photographs, 3.2
    - Portraits of Max Theiler (J. Blauvelt-Haulenbeek), undated (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Portraits of Max Theiler (J. Blauvelt-Haulenbeek), undated (Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Portraits of Max Theiler (J. Blauvelt-Haulenbeek), undated (Box 7, Folder 132)
      2 poses.
    - Portrait of Max Theiler (Agnes Baviello), undated (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Portraits of Max Theiler (Agnes Baviello), undated (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - Portraits of Max Theiler (Pach Brothers), undated (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Portraits of Max Theiler (General), 1920s; undated 1920 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Portrait of Max Theiler (Informal group), 1920s (Box 7, Folder 137)
      Max Theiler with Georges Ninaud and unidentified Harvard Medical School friend.
    - Portrait of Max Theiler and Elizabeth Theiler, 1940s (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Portraits of Max Theiler (Lasker Award Press Release), circa 1949 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Portraits of Max Theiler (Proofs, Pan-American Photo Service), 1951 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - Portrait of Max Theiler (Informal), 1951 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - Theiler Family Photos, 1900s-1955 (Box 7, Folder 142)
      Includes portrait of Margaret Theiler, 1928; Max Theiler family in Hasle, Switzerland, 1955?
    - Noguchi, Hideo (Bust), undated (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Pretoria Boys High School and Rhodes University College (Album), circa 1910-1916 (Box 8, Folder 144)
      Includes photos of Max Theiler.
    - Rockefeller Foundation Families, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - Trips: Egypt and India, 1951; 2 small albums and loose photos. (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - Trips: Latin America, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - Unidentified Portraits, undated (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Harvard African Expedition, 1926-1927; 433 prints. (Box 9, Folder 149)
      Note: Some of these photographs were published in Richard B. Strong, ed., The African Republic of Liberia and the Belgian Congo (2 vols., Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1930).
    - Portrait of Max Theiler (Conway Studios), undated (Box 10, Folder 150)
    - Portrait of Max Theiler (Pach Brothers), undated (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - Rhodes University College (Class Portrait), circa 1915-1916 (Box 10, Folder 152)
    - Album, circa 1934-1950s (Box 11, Folder 153)
      Max Theiler at the Rockefeller Institute Virus Laboratories; family photos; Rockefeller Foundation colleagues and families
- Ephemera, 4
  - Lasker Award, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Yale University Master of Arts Honorary Degree, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Nobel Prize Certificate, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Swiss Academy of Medical Sciences Honorary Diploma, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 157)
  - Hasle, Switzerland, Honorary Citizenship Certificate, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 158)
  - Certificate, University of the Cape of Good Hope, Matriculation Exam, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 159)
  - Clipping, "Yellowjack's Enemy Gets the Nobel Prize," Life magazine, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 160)